<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Feed Name</title>
  <link href="http://domain/"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://domain/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2015-04-23T17:39:04.1298986+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://domain/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Author</name>
    <email>Email</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <id>http://domain//2015/04/23/UseLDAPserver.html</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://domain//2015/04/23/UseLDAPserver.html"/>
    <title>Use LDAP server to authenticate user identity</title>
    <updated>2015-04-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Author</name>
      <uri>http://domain/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the group company, the employees&apos; account and password are all recorded in LDAP server, and usually there are SSO login needed, or the apps need login with the account exists in LDAP server. About the basic technology of LDAP server, you could search it from internet.  I just wanted to talk about &lt;strong&gt;how to use it to authenticate a user login&lt;/strong&gt;. And if your IT is really good at LDAP server and could told you about the LDAP structure, please ignore this article. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My situation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&apos;t know the base DN, and I don&apos;t know where to get that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know the LDAP server address and port, and lucky I get one of the LDAP server acccount could be used to search infos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steps to get LDAP structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download a LDAP server management tools(like Softerra LDAP Administrator)
   By default, it will login some LDAP servers, I am not if this only exists in Softera LdAP Administrator or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new profile to the LDAP server(notice the port).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/pucumt/pucumt.github.io/blob/master/Images/LDAP1.png?raw=true&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click next and input the account that could search in LDAP server
Usually the user will be cn=XXX or uid=XXX, that&apos;s both OK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/pucumt/pucumt.github.io/blob/master/Images/LDAP2.png?raw=true&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After input account, the LDAP structure will be displayed. And here is my LDAP structure:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/pucumt/pucumt.github.io/blob/master/Images/LDAP3.png?raw=true&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now it is easy to code with any computer language to authenticate a user exists or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for user password authenticate, you can try to find the way by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also a way to check your filter is correct or not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/pucumt/pucumt.github.io/blob/master/Images/LDAP4.png?raw=true&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://domain//2015/04/22/ThinkAboutCMMIAndAgile.html</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://domain//2015/04/22/ThinkAboutCMMIAndAgile.html"/>
    <title>CMMI还是Agile</title>
    <updated>2015-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Author</name>
      <uri>http://domain/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;开篇...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;软件项目管理到底用&lt;strong&gt;CMMI&lt;/strong&gt;还是&lt;strong&gt;Agile&lt;/strong&gt;呢？最近参加的各种活动会议毫无疑问推广的都是Agile，但是，实时上Agile是万能的吗？任何公司或者团队都可以照搬吗？事实证明Agile并不容易实施，失败的案例数不胜数。下面以我自己的观点分别分析一下这两种模式。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CMMI...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最著名的传统式软件开发莫过于V模型了，下面一张图摘自网络，很好的诠释了V模型的原理：
&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/pucumt/pucumt.github.io/blob/master/Images/V%20module.jpg?raw=true&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;整体结构非常公正，一环扣一环，层层把关，所以经过这样层层把关出来的东西有可能不完美，但是很少出现根本没法用的情况（当然如果你完全不了解V模式的合作方式另论）。说说整个项目中的人员吧：business，BSA，AD，PM，TL, Developers, Testers, Integration Team, Maintainance Team，有的还有PMO（or PMC）等等。有这么庞大的团队，功能职责这么全，很少出现出来的东西不能用的情况。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那是不是这样一种模式就是完美的呢？当然不是了，否则也不会出现敏捷模式的风靡了。归根到底在于这个团队太过于庞大，就如千军万马行动迟缓，一个改动要经过层层审批测试，一般这样的项目要一个季度以上才能发布一个release，而且个人的能力也比较难于得到体现。想想看我们另一个耳熟能详的模式原型模式，为什么传统开发非常少用这种模式呢？因为周期太长了，如果采用原型，肯定会延缓项目进度。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agile...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile的流行也有一段时间了，很多人都把敏捷奉若神明一样，什么样的人，什么样的团队都说自己是敏捷的，感觉敏捷就是高大上，能用少量的人解决一切问题。然而大家注意到没有，敏捷失败的案例非常的多。大家注意到的是敏捷的短迭代，没有那么多文档，没有那么多测试，所以开发团队很开心的在开发新功能，不太关心文档，不太关心测试，结果可想而知。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;优点&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;敏捷讲究的是迅速，也就是对时间的把控，所以用好了肯定要比传统开发快。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;敏捷对纪律性有一定的要求，要经常性的检查进度，这个也是我认为它效率高的主要原因。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;敏捷对成员有一定的要求，后续的检查没那么多，基本代码写定了，软件质量也就定了。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;敏捷虽然不要求那么多文档，但是至少要有一个大而全的文档，否则也不会出来那么多敏捷的软件了。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;敏捷也要跟踪，便于检查问题总结经验。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;缺点&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;敏捷对团队的能力有较高的要求，早期定位那些功能方向很重要。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;对团队要求高的另一点是简化的流程（集成，测试等等）并不是没有了，而是自动化了。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;如果有维护需求的项目容易导致进度难于控制（感觉这个算是真正的缺点）。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;如果每天对团队成员的时间管理过于紧张，容易引发负面情绪。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;留个小问题思考&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们听过的敏捷团队往往都很小的团队，如果你的项目很大，没法通过小团队来完成，需要多个团队协同完成，那怎么去敏捷这个大的团队呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;总结...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最近参与了IBM的敏捷活动，发现某些公司完全没有章程的开发才是最大的问题，自上而下完全不懂软件工程，人员能力比较一般，对上埋怨领导想到啥提啥，对下埋怨工作进度质量差。跟自己的工作经历结合，有感而发，有些未必对。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;总之，采取那么开发模式最好对软件工程有一些认知，选用那些软件管理项目，根据自身的成本考虑，没有说收费的就一定比免费的好，所以选择对的才是最重要。而且我比较反对敏捷采用8小时Charge的方式，压力太大。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://domain//2015/04/20/myfirstpost.html</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://domain//2015/04/20/myfirstpost.html"/>
    <title>My First Blog to use GitHub</title>
    <updated>2015-04-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Author</name>
      <uri>http://domain/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;About github...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github&lt;/strong&gt; is really famous now, not only for &lt;strong&gt;open source&lt;/strong&gt;, but also for &lt;strong&gt;static blogs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is the first time for me to try to use github to publish my blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried some static blog projects such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://hexo.io/docs/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hexo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (made with node.js), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gohugo.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hugo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (made with golang), of course the first try is &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jekyll&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (made with Ruby), but at the end I still choose &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Code52/pretzel&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pretzel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(made by C#). The reason why I choose this because I am familiar with C#, and also it has a wonderful IDE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principal commands are the following but more informations are available on the wiki&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; is used to create the folder structure for a new site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretzel create
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the site should be at a specific folder, this can be specified as a parameter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretzel create C:\path\to\folder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bake&lt;/strong&gt; is used to generate a site based on the contents of a folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To scan the current directory for a website and detect the content to process, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretzel bake 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To scan a specific folder and parse the contents, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretzel bake C:\path\to\folder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To explicitly specify the input - we should support inferring the input based on the files found anyway - run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretzel bake --engine liquid
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taste&lt;/strong&gt; is for testing a site locally - make a change, and pretzel should handle regenerating the page when a file changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test a site locally, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretzel taste 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To specify the port to serve the site from (default will be 4000), run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretzel taste --port 5000
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stop the site, press q.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>